Brainard E. Prescott Collection
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Brainard E. Prescott Collection
1866 - 1935
1 box + 1 slim box (0.75 linear ft.)
Prescott, Brainard E.
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Administrative agencies Reorganization; African American Education; Cooke, Elizabeth; broadsides (notices); Harrison, Jonas, 1777-1836; County government Law and legislation; Erie County Survey Commission (N.Y.); Harrison County (Tex.); Johnson, Andrew, 1808-1875; Kenefick, Daniel J., 1863-1949; Scovell, Josiah Boardman, 1869 or 70-1960; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Standing Committee on Judiciary; Reconstruction; Scovell, OP; Smith, Gerrit, 1797-1874; Slavery United States Emancipation; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915; Temperance United States, Societies, etc.; Texas History; Tuskegee Institute; United States History Civil War, 1861-1865; Williams, Harrison; Asbury, Samuel E. (Samuel Erson), 1872-1962
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
Erie County Survey Commission was created in 1934 to investigate the reorganization of the county government. Its chairman was the Hon. Daniel J. Kenefick. It issued a report detailing its plan to the Board of Supervisors and the general public in March 1935. Gerrit Smith resided in Peterboro (N.H.?) at the time of these writings and was a strong supporter of emancipation and African American rights. Upon his death the African American citizens of Buffalo paid him a formal tribute. Booker T. Washington founded the Tuskegee Normal and Industrial Institute for the education of young African Americans in 1881 in Tuskegee Institute, Alabama; served as its principal from 1881 to 1915. Jonas Harrison was the founder of Harrison County, Texas. Before moving to Texas, he had been the first lawyer in Lewiston, NY, and collector of the Port of Entry; he was the husband of Elizabeth Cooke and was a prominent figure in Buffalo.
Erie County Survey Commission for reorganization of county government (Kenefick Commission): hearing transcripts and allied material, 1933-1935; letters and broadsides by Gerrit Smith, 1866-1869; letters of Booker T. Washington from the Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, 1908-1911; and letters and papers, 1932-1933, about the life of Jonas Harrison.
Consists of four separate and unrelated manuscript collections: I. Erie County Survey Commission records. II. Gerrit Smith papers. III. Booker T. Washington letters. IV. Jonas Harrison collection. Arranged chronologically within each sub-unit.
- Series I: Erie County Survey Commission (=the Kenefick Commission), 1933-1935 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Vol. 1: The Senate Committee on Judiciary hearing on County government legislation, Mr. Parker's Copy, March 20, 1934
  - Vol. 2: Correspondence, financial records and meeting minutes
  - Folder 1: Erie County Survey Commission: Resolution and newspaper clippings, 1934-1935
- Series II: Smith, Gerrit, 1866-1871 (Box-folder 2.1-2.2)
  - Folder 1: Gerrit Smith broadsides, 1866-1869
  - Folder 2: Ten Gerrit Smith letters to O.P. Scovell, 1868-1871
- Series III: Washington, Booker T., 1908-1911 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Folder 3: Four Booker T. Washington letters to J. Boardman Scovell, 1908-1911
- Series IV: Harrison, Jonas, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 2.4-2.5)
  - Folder 4: Letters re: Jonas Harrison, 1932 - 1933
  - Folder 5: Letters re: Jonas Harrison, undated materials